bostonmarathon.org 2019-04-16

# Privacy Policy | Boston Athletic Association

All materials and content included on this web site are copyrighted and may not be reproduced, stored in or reintroduced into a retrieval system, or retransmitted in any form or by any means (electronic, mechanical, recording or otherwise) for commercial purposes without the prior written permission of both the owner and the above publisher of this web site.

Boston Marathon, B.A.A. Marathon, and the B.A.A. Unicorn logo are registered trademarks of the Boston Athletic Association. Use of these trademarks without written permission from the Boston Athletic Association is prohibited.

The Boston Athletic Association does not authorize the use of photographs posted on www.baa.org. All inquires for use of the photographs at this web site will be referred to the owner of the materials in question. The owners of the photographs have authorized the use of these photographs by the B.A.A. only. This use is limited to the web site only.

### PRIVACY POLICY

_Effective August 20, 2018_

The Boston Athletic Association (“ _B.A.A._ ,” “ _we_ ,” or “ _us_ ”) respects the privacy of our athletes, volunteers, website visitors, and other individuals. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, and share information in connection with our websites (“ _Websites_ ”) and our mobile applications (“ _Apps_ ”) (collectively, the “ _Services_ ”). It also explains your rights and choices with respect to such information and the steps you can take to protect your privacy.

Please read this policy carefully and let us know if you have any questions. By visiting or using the Services, installing our Apps, clicking “I agree” or any other button indicating your acceptance of this Privacy Policy, or otherwise providing information to B.A.A., you are consenting to the collection, use, and sharing of your information as described in this Privacy Policy.

The information that we collect in connection with our Services is controlled by the Boston Athletic Association, which is headquartered in the United States at 185 Dartmouth Street, 6th floor, Boston, Massachusetts 02116. As a result, such information may be transferred to and processed in the United States, as described in the section below titled “Information for Individuals Outside the United States.”

##### Information that We Collect

We and our service providers collect a variety of information through the Services, including:

  * _Account and profile information._ We collect information when you create an account or edit your profile, such as your name, username, password, email address, race history, and volunteer experience.
  * _Event registration or volunteer information._ We collect information when you register or volunteer for a race or other event, such as your name, address, email address, phone number, country of residence, citizenship, age or date of birth, gender, race history and experience, club affiliation, occupation, emergency contacts, and self-reported disability status, proof of disability, or other health-related information that you provide directly to us as necessary for participation in a race or other event. Our third-party service providers may also collect your payment card information when you submit your registration.
  * _Race activities and results._ We collect information when you participate in a race or other event that we organize. For example, we may collect information about your real-time location during a race (such as your progress along the course), your race times and splits, and your finishing results. We may share this information with the general public through our Services, as described in the section below titled “How We Share Information.”
  * _Information you provide to us directly or through the Services._ We collect information that you provide to us directly or through the Services, such as when you post questions or comments, respond to surveys, rate the Apps, or communicate with us.
  * _Information collected automatically._ When you use our Services, we or our third-party service providers may automatically receive and record certain information. For example, this may include your device’s IP address, user-agent string, information about your use of the Services during your current session and over time (including the pages you view and the files you download), the date and time of your visit, links you click, searches conducted, the website visited before navigating to the Services, your software and hardware attributes (including browser and operating system type and version, App version, device type, and device identifiers), and your general location inferred from IP address. To obtain such information, we or our third-party service providers may use the following technologies to recognize your device and collect information about your Services usage:
  * __Server logs.__ When you use the Services, we automatically receive and record certain information from your computer (or other device) and your browser. To obtain such information, we may use server logs or applications that recognize your device and gather information about its online activity.
  * __Cookies.__ We also use cookies on the Services. Cookies are small files that are stored on your device by your web browser. A cookie allows us to recognize whether you have visited before and may store user preferences and other information. If you are concerned about having cookies on your device, you can set your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being set, allowing you to decide whether to accept it. You can also delete cookies from your device. However, if you choose to block or delete cookies, certain features of the Services may not operate correctly. 
    * __Web beacons, tags, pixels, and similar technologies.__ The Services or the emails that you receive from us may use an application known as a “web beacon” (also known as a “tag” or “pixel”) and similar technologies. Web beacons are small strings of code that provide a method for delivering a graphic image on a web page or in an email message for the purpose of transferring data. For example, it may allow an email sender to determine whether a user has opened a particular email.
  * __Mobile advertising IDs_._ We may use mobile advertising identifiers (such as Apple’s IDFA or Google’s Advertising ID) to collect information for analytics purposes, as described in the section below titled “Third-Party Analytics.”

We may combine information collected through the Services with information that we collect in other contexts, such as information from our email communications or phone calls with you, or data that we collect at races and events. We also may collect information about your race eligibility, race qualifying information (such as information related to your past participation in other races), and factors that may disqualify you from participating in a race. We will treat such combined information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

##### How We Use Information that We Collect

We and our service providers use the information that we collect for a variety of purposes, including:

  * _Providing the Services._ To provide our Services to you, organize races and events, fulfill the terms of any agreement you have with us, respond to your requests, and for other purposes related to managing our organization;
  * _Communicating with you._ To communicate with you regarding your account, events for which you have registered or volunteered, important updates regarding our Services, and other administrative issues;
  * _Sending B.A.A. newsletters or other promotional messages._ To send you newsletters or other promotional messages regarding our Services and the events that we organize;
  * _Enabling community features._ To allow you to ask questions, post comments, and communicate with other users on the Services;
  * _Tailoring our content and advertisements._ To tailor content on the Services and target our advertising;
  * _Conducting analytics and improving our services._ To count and recognize visitors to the Services, analyze how visitors use the Services, improve the Services, create new products and services, and conduct analytics, including as described in the section below titled “Third-Party Analytics”;
  * _Compiling aggregated and de-identified information._ To compile aggregated and de-identified statistics or reports that we may share with our partners or other third parties;
  * _Legal purposes._ For legal or other necessary purposes, including as described below in the section below titled “How We Share information.”

##### How We Share Information

We share information with third parties for a variety of reasons, including as follows:

  * _Service providers._ We use third-party service providers to help us manage and improve our Services and organize races and events. These service providers may collect and use your information to assist us in achieving the purposes discussed in this Privacy Policy. For example, we may use third parties to assist with race events, mail printed materials to runners or volunteers, communicate with runners or volunteers, perform data storage and processing services, process payments on our behalf, tailor our advertising, and perform analytics, including as described in the section below tiled “Third-Party Analytics.”
  * _Other users of the Services._ We may allow you to share information directly with other users of the Services. For example, if you post questions or comments to other users through the Services, add information to your profile, respond to surveys or requests to rate the Apps, or use other features of the Services, then your questions, comments, profile, or other information may be seen by other users of the Services. Please ensure when using these features that you do not submit any information that you do not want to be shared with other users or the public.
  * _Our partners._ We may share information about final race results with our partners, including other non-profit organizations, sports organizations, or researchers who may use the final race results to confirm race eligibility/disqualification, generate reports, or conduct academic research.
  * _Live updates and final race results._ If you participate in a race that we organize, we may share certain information about you with the general public. For example, we may share your name, age group, gender, state and country of residence, and final race results through our Websites and Apps. We also may share your real-time location during a race (such as your progress along the course), race times and splits, and final results so that others can track your progress.
  * _Third-party plugins._ The Services may integrate certain third-party plugins (such as a Facebook “like” button and Twitter “follow” button). Even if you do not click on these plugins, they may collect information about you, such as your IP address and the pages that you view. They also may set and/or access a cookie or use similar tracking technologies. These plugins are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them.
  * _Legal purposes._ We may use or share your information with third parties when we believe, in our sole reasonable discretion, that doing so is necessary: 
    * To comply with applicable law or a court order, subpoena, or other legal process;
    * To investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or prohibited activities, suspected fraud, violations of our rules or terms and conditions, or situations involving threats to other athletes, volunteers or users, our property, or the property or physical safety of any person or third party;
    * To establish, protect, or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.
  * _Organizational transfers._ We may share your information with third parties to facilitate the financing, securitization, insuring, merger, acquisition, sale, assignment, bankruptcy, or other disposal of all or part of our organization or assets.
  * _Aggregated and de-identified information._ We may share aggregated and de-identified information with third parties, such as by publishing or sharing reports with third parties about trends in the usage of the B.A.A. Services.

##### Third-Party Analytics

We partner with certain third parties to collect information to engage in analytics, auditing, research, and reporting. These third parties may use server logs, web beacons, tags, pixels, mobile advertising IDs (such as Apple’s IDFA or Google’s Advertising ID), and similar technologies, and they may set and access cookies on your computer or other device. In particular, our Services use Google Analytics to help collect and analyze certain information for the purposes discussed above. You may learn more about Google Analytics’ data practices by clicking [here](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html) and opt out of the use of cookies in web browsers by Google Analytics by clicking [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

Please note that our Services do not respond to browser Do Not Track signals at this time.

##### Third-Party Links, Websites, and Apps

The Services may contain links to websites or mobile apps of other third parties, including social media sharing features that link to third-party websites. If you follow a link to any of these websites or apps, please note that these websites and apps (and any services that may be accessible through them) have their own privacy policies. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites or apps or the information you share through such other websites or apps. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave the Services and to read the privacy policies applicable to such third-party websites and apps. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected in connection with the Services.

##### Data Security and Retention

B.A.A. uses reasonable physical, technical, and administrative safeguards to protect your information against loss or unauthorized access, use, modification, or deletion. However, no security program is 100% secure, and thus we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your information.

B.A.A. retains your information for as long as reasonably necessary for its legitimate business purposes, to provide the Services to you, to fulfill the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, or as required by law.

##### Your Rights and Choices

B.A.A. provides you with choices to review, access, and update your information or to exercise your data protection rights, as follows:

  * If you no longer want to receive our newsletters or other promotional communications from B.A.A., please follow the “unsubscribe” instructions that are included at the bottom of each message. Please note that if you unsubscribe from our promotional communications, you will still receive administrative messages from us.
  * If you are a California resident under 18 years of age and a registered user of our Services, you may request that we remove content and information that you post on our Services. To obtain removal of such content and information, please send us an email to [info@baa.org](mailto:info@baa.org) with a short description of the content or information you would like to have removed. Please note that such a request does not necessarily ensure complete or comprehensive removal of content posted by you, since the content and information may remain in our or our service provider’s databases, may remain visible in a manner that does not identify you, or may have been re-posted by another user.
  * You may have additional rights under applicable laws to request access to, correction of, deletion of, or restrictions on the processing of certain information. You also may have rights under applicable laws to opt out of or withdraw consent to further processing, request copies of your data, or lodge a complaint with a data protection authority in your jurisdiction. To make such request and/or inquire about such rights, please send us an email at [info@baa.org](mailto:info@baa.org) with “Attn: Privacy/Legal” in the subject line. For your protection, we may only implement requests related to information that we have associated with the email address you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request.

##### Information for Individuals Outside the United States

The information that we collect through or in connection with our Services may be transferred to and processed in the United States for the purposes described above. B.A.A. also may subcontract the processing of your data to, or otherwise share your data with, third parties in the United States or other countries outside your country of residence. The data protection laws in these countries may be different from, and less stringent than, those in your country of residence. By visiting or using the Services, installing our Apps, clicking “I agree” or any other button indicating your acceptance of this Privacy Policy, or otherwise providing information to B.A.A., you explicitly consent to such transfer and processing.

We may implement standard contractual clauses, contractual arrangements, or other mechanisms, as appropriate, to safeguard your information during such cross-border transfers. We also may transfer information to the United States or another country as necessary for the performance of our agreements with you or to establish, exercise, or defend legal claims.

If you are an EU resident, our legal basis for processing information will depend on the type of information at issue and the purpose for which it is collected and used. In many cases, we rely on your consent to process information, or we process information as necessary for the performance of our agreements with you. We also may rely on our legitimate interests to process your information, for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, except where such interests are overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms.

##### Children’s Privacy

The Services are not intended for nor directed to individuals that are deemed to be children under applicable data protection or privacy laws. We request that such individuals do not provide information to us through any of the Services.

##### Sensitive Information

We ask that you not send us, and you not disclose, any sensitive information ( _e.g_., social security numbers, financial account information, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, genetic or biometric data, or sexual orientation) on or through the Services or otherwise to us, except for self-reported disability status, proof of disability, or other health-related information that you provide directly to us as necessary for participation in a race or other event.

##### Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may revise this Privacy Policy periodically in the future. If we make any material changes, we will post the revised Privacy Policy on our Websites and in our Apps under “Settings,” with an effective date indicating when the revised Privacy Policy will take effect. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically.

##### Contacting Us

If you have any questions or comments regarding our Privacy Policy, please email us at [info@baa.org](mailto:info@baa.org) with “Attn: Privacy/Legal” in the subject line or contact us by mail at:  
Boston Athletic Association  
Attn: Privacy/Legal  
185 Dartmouth Street  
6th floor  
Boston MA 02116
